

# **Domenico Camasta**

✓ domenicocamasta@gmail.com 📞 3701522690 💡 Via F. Baracca 8 🏥 29/12/1983

■ Italian

♣ He/Him ★ portfolio.devcrumbs.com ♠ d-cmst

#### **Profile**

I'm a mathematician by education and self-taught software developer for passion, with over 10 years of experience building full-stack web applications with Python, JavaScript, React, Node.js and PHP. My expertise also includes systems administration and databases management/optimization.

I'm currently trying to rebase in Bologna after some years abroad, looking for job opportunities in/near the city.

## **Professional Experience**

**Developer,** *UserTesting* □

2018 - 12/2022

Creating and executing usability tests to evaluate the ease of use, efficiency, and overall user experience of software products: designing test plans, coding test scripts, recruiting test participants, and analyzing test results.

UK | Germany | Remote

**Developer,** Appen Ltd Chatbot software development. 2020 - 2022

Remote

**Project Manager,** *UniD Formazione* □

2015 - 2018

Development, deployment and system administration for the company web applications.

Borgo Maggiore, RSM

Teacher, MIUR □

2011 - 2014

Mathematics/Logic teacher for high school and university students.

Verona, Italy

#### Languages

Italian Native

**English** 

**TOEFL 2020** 

## **Education**

PhD, Università "La Sapienza"

2007 - 2010

PhD Program in Mathematical Logic | Thesis title: "A two-dimensional semantics for natural language formalization"

Rome, Italy

Master Degree, Università Degli Studi di Genova Italian Master Degree (Laurea Magistrale) – Mathematics 2002 - 2007

Genova, Italy

#### **Certificates**

**TOEFL** 

Test date: 2020

Score: 98/120 (Advanced)

## PCAP - Certified Associate in Python Programming

ID: 383260354

Validation: 338962730

Score: 92%

## **Projects**

#### **AGReATWine**, *Contributor* □

2020 - present

Creation of a database of Italian wines included in DOCG appellations, evaluated by the three main national wine guides

## **KDE,** Contributor, Member □

2005 - present

Code, designs and translations for many desktop applications and web applications from the KDE ecosystem.

#### **ArchLinux,** *Package mantainer* □

2005 - present

Arch Linux is a Linux distribution that tries to Keep It Simple

#### WireGuard, Contributor ☑

2020 - 2022

WireGuard is an extremely simple yet fast and modern VPN

#### **GSConnect,** Contributor □

Complete implementation of KDE Connect especially for GNOME Shell.

## **InvoicePlane,** *Contributor* □

A self-hosted open source application for managing your invoices, clients and payments.

#### RAMP, Contributor

Ramp is a python library for rapid prototyping of machine learning solutions. It's a light-weight pandas-based machine learning framework pluggable with existing python machine learning and statistics tools.

## Wiki.js, Patch contributor □

Wiki.js is a modern and powerful wiki app built on Node.js

## **Publications**

Collana UnidTest, Libri per la preparazione dei test di ammissione universitari

#### Other certificates

## Italian Sommelier Association - Diploma 🛮

01/2020

Diploma di Sommelier rilasciato dall'Associazione Italiana Sommelier

Bologna, Italy